MAITRI SHAH

DESIGN LEADER

SKILLS

Creative Direction Design Systems Product Design Interaction Design **Design Sprints** People Management Product Management **Process Implementation Process Improvement** CX Strategy Adobe CC Wireframing HTML/CSS/JS Workshops **UX** Research

CERTIFICATIONS

UX Strategy for Emerging Technologies New York University 2020

Product Management General Assembly 2018

Sharepoint 2016 Power End User **ONLC Training Center** 2016

Web Development Immersive General Assembly 2015

PROFILE

Passionate about people, product and process. Design professional with 15 years of experience in design, with 9+ years in product, UX, and UI design for diverse organizations. Possesses uniquely effective ability to enhance performance of teams due to choreography and teaching experience, as well as formal education in design, business and information technology. Passionate about empowering teams to exceed expectations and progressively raise the bar. Entrepreneurial thinker who gets excited by empathizing with users and creating value for them.

EDUCATION

Information Technology, Digital Media and Instructional Design MS Harvard University (HES) 2013, Partially Completed

Finance BS Michigan State University 2003-2007

Apparel & Textile Design BA Michigan State University 2003-2007

Fashion Design Fashion Institute of Technology 2005-2006

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE IS ON THE NEXT PAGE ----

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UX Design Manager, Fuego UX - Remote - Jan 2022-current

Currently manages design teams, working with various clients concurrently on complex products and digital experiences. Communicates across different audiences at varying levels of different organizations with focus on efficient process, effective collaboration and results that create value for the user.

Global Managing Lead, Design Systems, Gallagher - Chicago, IL - Jul 2021-current

Currently leads self-initiated transformational effort across large-scale organization to create and manage design systems for portfolio of global brands with consideration to both systems users' and end users' needs. Recruits talent and is building out first ever in-house design team. Harmonizes efforts within design team along with those of research, content, dev and web operations by optimizing logistics, placing the right people at the right position at the right time to execute the tactics necessary to achieve the strategic objective.

Interactive Design Lead / Manager, Outfront Media - New York, NY - Jul 2019-Jul 2021

Manager of design team responsible for digital initiatives including customer-facing products and experiences, including emerging technology. Collaborated as strategic partner to engineering, implementation, marketing and content leads. Built and maintained design systems to empower systems users.

Created CX strategy as part of business development, helping to win multi-million dollar contracts with the MBTA and CTA. This was added as a new revenue-generating capability of the department.

Led teams on the UX, UI, Art and CMS tracks to design and produce VR app for clients. Voluntarily produced and hosted creative events to help enhance creative culture, where attendance doubled over time due to interest from technology and content teams.

Design Consultant, Havas North America - New York, NY - Jun 2019-Jul 2019

Selected to work directly with the CEO of Havas North America, CEO of Havas New York and with a team of creatives on a creative storytelling project to digitally represent Havas North America and its 26 entities.

Led a team to create a concept and design system documentation to distribute globally as creative direction.

Senior UI/UX Designer, Practising Law Institute - New York, NY - Nov 2015-Jan 2019

Partnered with cross functional teams in an Agile setting to enhance design on client-facing interfaces with a focus on accessible design. Self-initiated the creation of a request system between the marketing and graphic design teams consisting of 25+ team members, including a centralized system and request process which materially improved department's visibility into requests and increased productivity. Collaborated with the CMO on change management and continued support.

UX/UI Designer, AIQ - New York, NY - Jun 2013-Jul 2015

Played integral role in developing the brand identity by extending the branding into a visual language for print and digital marketing materials, digital billboard content for 13 screens in Times Square and a registration website for a corporate event.

Business Owner and Designer, Freelance - New York, NY - Aug 2007-Jun 2013

Self-created dance practice including performance, choreography and teaching in the NY tristate area. Created designs for NIKE, Custo Barcelona and Steve & Barry's.

